I love a challenge, and saving the Earth is probably a good one.
يععجبني التحدي، و لعل إنقاذ الأرض خير تحد
We all know the Earth is in trouble.
كلنا نعلم أن الكرة الأرضية في خطر
We have now entered in the 6X,
لقد دخلنا الآن العصر السادس
the sixth major extinction on this planet.
الانقراض السادس العظيم على هذا الكوكب
I often wondered, if there was a United Organization of Organisms --
أحيانا أتسائل ما إذا كان هناك منظمة الكائنات المتحدة
otherwise known as "Uh-Oh" --
أو المعروفة باسم "Uh-Oh"
(Laughter) -- and every organism had a right to vote,
(ضحك) -- و لكل كائن حق التصويت
would we be voted on the planet, or off the planet?
هل يا ترى سيتم التصويت بإبقائنا أو رحيلنا؟
I think that vote is occurring right now.
أعتقد أن التصويت يجري الآن
I want to present to you a suite of six mycological solutions,
أريد أن أقدم لكم مجموعة ٦ حلول فطرية
using fungi, and these solutions are based on mycelium.
باستخدام الفطريات، و هذه الحلول مرتكزة على الميسيليوم
The mycelium infuses all landscapes,
الميسيليوم تخترق جميع المسطحات
it holds soils together, it's extremely tenacious.
إنها تمسك التربة معا. هي في غاية التماسك
This holds up to 30,000 times its mass.
هذه تستوعب ٣٠٠٠٠ مقدار كتلتها
They're the grand molecular disassemblers of nature -- the soil magicians.
هم المفككون الجزيئيون العظيمون للطبيعة -- سحرة التربة
They generate the humus soils across the landmasses of Earth.
ينتجون أتربة الدبال عبر مساحات اليابسة للأرض
We have now discovered that there is a multi-directional transfer
لقد اكتشفنا الآن أن أن هناك انتقال متعدد الاتجاهات
of nutrients between plants, mitigated by the mcyelium --
للمواد الغذائية بين النباتات، مخففة بواسطة الميسيليوم
so the mycelium is the mother
فالميسيليوم هي الأم
that is giving nutrients from alder and birch trees
التي تعطي المواد الغذائية من أشجار جار الماء و البيتولا
to hemlocks, cedars and Douglas firs.
إلى الشوكران و الأرز و دوغلاس التنوب
Dusty and I, we like to say, on Sunday, this is where we go to church.
أنا و دستي، نحب أن نقول أن هذا بمثابة زيارة الكنيسة يوم الأحد بالنسبة لنا
I'm in love with the old-growth forest,
أنا مغرم بالغابة القديمة
and I'm a patriotic American because we have those.
و أنا أمريكي وطني لأننا نملك هذه الغابات
Most of you are familiar with Portobello mushrooms.
معظمكم يألف فطر البورتابيلو
And frankly, I face a big obstacle.
و بصراحة أواجه صعوبة كبيرة
When I mention mushrooms to somebody,
عندما أذكر الفطريات لأحد
they immediately think Portobellos or magic mushrooms,
على الفور يخطر لهم فطر البورتابيلو أو المشرووم
their eyes glaze over, and they think I'm a little crazy.
تحدق عيونهم ويعتقدون بأنني مجنون بعض الشيء
So, I hope to pierce that prejudice forever with this group.
فأتمنى أن أخرق هذا التحامل من خلال هذه المجموعة
We call it mycophobia,
نسميها فوبيا الفطريات
the irrational fear of the unknown, when it comes to fungi.
الخوف اللامنطقي من المجهول بالنسبة للفطريات
Mushrooms are very fast in their growth.
الفطريات سريعة النمو
Day 21, day 23, day 25.
اليوم ال ٢١، ال ٢٣، ال ٢٥
Mushrooms produce strong antibiotics.
تنتج الفطريات مضادات حيوية قوية
In fact, we're more closely related to fungi than we are to any other kingdom.
في الواقع، نحن أكثر قرابة للفطريات مما نحن لأي مملكة أخرى
A group of 20 eukaryotic microbiologists
مجموعة مكونة من ٢٠ عالم أحياء دقيقة حقيقيات النوى
published a paper two years ago erecting opisthokonta --
قاموا بإصدار مقالة منذ عامين أنشئوا مجموعة الأوبثكونوتا
a super-kingdom that joins animalia and fungi together.
عبارة عن مملكة عظمى تجمع مملكتي الحيوانات و الفطريات سويا
We share in common the same pathogens.
نشترك معا في مسببات الأمراض
Fungi don't like to rot from bacteria,
الفطريات لا تحب أن تتعفن من البكتيريا
and so our best antibiotics come from fungi.
و بالتالي فإن أفضل مضادتنا الحيوية تأتي من الفطريات
But here is a mushroom that's past its prime.
و لكن هنا فطر قد تعدى أوجه
After they sporulate, they do rot.
بعد أن ينتجوا أبواغا، يتعفنون
But I propose to you that the sequence of microbes
ولكنني أقترح إليكم بأن تسلسل الجراثيم
that occur on rotting mushrooms
التي تظهر على الفطر المتعفنة
are essential for the health of the forest.
مهمة لصحة الغابة
They give rise to the trees,
إنهم ينتجون الأشجار
they create the debris fields that feed the mycelium.
تخلق حقول الأنقاض التي تغذي الميسليوم
And so we see a mushroom here sporulating.
فنرى فطرا هنا ينتج بوغا
And the spores are germinating,
و الأبواغ تنتج برعم
and the mycelium forms and goes underground.
و تتشكل الميسليوم و تذهب تحت الأرض
In a single cubic inch of soil, there can be more than eight miles of these cells.
في الانش المكعب الواحد، من الممكن أن يكون هناك أكثر من ٨ أميال من هذه الخلايا
My foot is covering approximately 300 miles of mycelium.
قدمي تغطي حوالي ٣٠٠ ميل من الميسيليوم
This is photomicrographs from Nick Read and Patrick Hickey.
هذه الصور المجهرية من نيك ريد و باتريك هكي
And notice that as the mycelium grows,
و لاحظوا أن حيث تنمو الميسيليوم
it conquers territory and then it begins the net.
تتحكم بالمنطقة ثم تبدأ بتشكيل الشباك
I've been a scanning electron microscopist for many years,
لعدة سنوات عملت كعالم مجهر مسح الكتروني
I have thousands of electron micrographs,
لدي الآلاف من الصور المجهرية الالكترونية
and when I'm staring at the mycelium,
و عندما أحدق في الميسيليوم
I realize that they are microfiltration membranes.
ألاحظ أنهم أغشية تصفية مصغرة
We exhale carbon dioxide, so does mycelium.
نحن نطلق غاز ثاني أكسيد الكربون، وكذلك تفعل الميسليوم
It inhales oxygen, just like we do.
تستنشق الأكسجين، تماما كما نفعل
But these are essentially externalized stomachs and lungs.
و لكن هذه في الحقيقة معدات و رئات خارجية
And I present to you a concept that these are extended neurological membranes.
و أنا أتقدم لكم بفكرة أنهم أغشية عصبية ممتدة
And in these cavities, these micro-cavities form,
و في هذه التجاويف تتشكل تجاويف مصغرة
and as they fuse soils, they absorb water.
و عندما يخلطون الأتربة، يمتصون الماء
These are little wells.
هذه آبار صغيرة
And inside these wells, then microbial communities begin to form.
و داخل هذه الآبار تبدأ وحدات جرثومية بالتشكل
And so the spongy soil not only resists erosion,
و بالتالي فإن التربة الاسفنجية لا تقاوم التآكل فحسب
but sets up a microbial universe
بل تهيأ عالم جرثومي
that gives rise to a plurality of other organisms.
التي تنتج بدورها كائنتات متعددة
I first proposed, in the early 1990s,
قمت بالاقتراح، في بداية التسعينيات
that mycelium is Earth's natural Internet.
بأن الميسيليوم هي الانترنت الطبيعي للكرة الأرضية
When you look at the mycelium, they're highly branched.
عندما تنظر إلى الميسيليوم، تجد أنها كثيرة التفرع
And if there's one branch that is broken, then very quickly,
وإذا كان هناك فرع مكسور، فسريعا
because of the nodes of crossing --
بسبب تقاطع العناقيد -ـ
Internet engineers maybe call them hot points --
مهندسو الانترنت قد يسمونها النقاط الساخنة -ـ
there are alternative pathways for channeling nutrients and information.
هناك مسارات بديلة لتوجيه المواد الغذائية و المعلومات
The mycelium is sentient.
الميسيليوم حساسة
It knows that you are there.
تعرف أنك موجود
When you walk across landscapes,
عندما تمشي عبر المسطحات
it leaps up in the aftermath of your footsteps trying to grab debris.
فإنها تقفر بعد خظواتك محاولة التعلق بالبقايا
So, I believe the invention of the computer Internet
لذلك أعتقد أن اختراع انترنت الكمبيوتر
is an inevitable consequence
نتيجة حتمية
of a previously proven, biologically successful model.
لنموذج بيولوجي سابق مثبت النجاح
The Earth invented the computer Internet for its own benefit,
الكرة الأرضية اخترعت الانترنت لصالحها
and we now, being the top organism on this planet,
و نحن الآن، باعتبارنا أعلى كائن على هذا الكوكب
are trying to allocate resources in order to protect the biosphere.
نحاول تخصيص الموارد من أجل حماية المحيط الحيوي
Going way out, dark matter conforms to the same mycelial archetype.
بعيدا عن هذا، المادة المظلمة تخضع لنفس هذا النموذج الميسيلي
I believe matter begets life;
أعتقد أن المادة تولد الحياة
life becomes single cells; single cells become strings;
الحياة تصبح خلايا وحيدة، الخلايا الوحيدة تصبح خيوطا
strings become chains; chains network.
الخيوط تصبح سلاسل، السلاسل تتشابك
And this is the paradigm that we see throughout the universe.
وهذا هو النموذج الذي نراه في جميع أنحاء الكون
Most of you may not know that fungi were the first organisms to come to land.
معظمكم قد لا يعلم أن الفطريات هي أول الكائنات على سطح الأرض
They came to land 1.3 billion years ago,
أتوا إلى اليابسة منذ ١،٣ مليار سنة
and plants followed several hundred million years later.
ثم تبعتها النباتات بعد مئات الملايين من السنين
How is that possible?
كيف يمكن ذلك؟
It's possible because the mycelium produces oxalic acids,
إنه ممكن لأن الميسيلبوم تنتج أحماض الأكسليت
and many other acids and enzymes,
و أحماض و إنزيمات عديدة أخرى
pockmarking rock and grabbing calcium and other minerals
تاركة علامات على الصخور و منتزعة الكالسيوم ومعادن الأخرى
and forming calcium oxalates.
و مشكلة أكسليت الكالسيوم
Makes the rocks crumble, and the first step in the generation of soil.
تجعل الصخور تنهار، والخطوة الأولى في انتاج التربة
Oxalic acid is two carbon dioxide molecules joined together.
الحمض الأكسليكي عبارة عن جزيئان ثاني أكسيد الكربون
So, fungi and mycelium
إذا الفطريات و الميسيليوم
sequester carbon dioxide in the form of calcium oxalates.
تقوم بعزل ثاني أكسيد الكربون على شكل أكسالات الكالسيوم
And all sorts of other oxalates
وأنواع أخرى عدديدة من الأكسالات
are also sequestering carbon dioxide through the minerals
تقوم أيضا بعزل ثاني أكسيد الكربون من خلال المعادن
that are being formed and taken out of the rock matrix.
المتشكلة و المأخوذة من قالب الصخرة
This was first discovered in 1859.
تم هذا الاكتشاف عام ١٨٥٩
This is a photograph by Franz Hueber.
هذه الصورة التقطها فرانز هيوبر
This photograph's taken 1950s in Saudi Arabia.
هذه الصورة مأخوذة في الخمسينيات في المملكة العربية السعودية
420 million years ago, this organism existed.
منذ ٤٢٠ مليون عاما كان هذا الكائن موجودا
It was called Prototaxites.
كان يسمى بالبروتوتكسايتس
Prototaxites, laying down, was about three feet tall.
البروتوتكسايتس، نائمة، كانت بإرتفاع ٣ أقدام
The tallest plants on Earth at that time were less than two feet.
أطول نباتات في ذلك الوقت على الأرض كانت أقل من قدمين
Dr. Boyce, at the University of Chicago,
د. بويس في جامعة شيكاغو
published an article in the Journal of Geology
أصدر مقالة في مجلة الجيولوجيا
this past year determining that Prototaxites was a giant fungus,
في العام الماضي مأكدين أن البروتوتاكسايس كان فطرا كبيرا
a giant mushroom.
عش غراب كبير
Across the landscapes of Earth were dotted these giant mushrooms.
عبر مسطحات الأرض قد بانت فطريات كبيرة
All across most land masses.
عبر معظم مساحات اليابسة
And these existed for tens of millions of years.
و هؤلاء تواجدوا لعشرات الملايين من السنين
Now, we've had several extinction events, and as we march forward --
الآن لدينا عدة أحداث انقراض، و حيث نمضي قدما -ـ
65 million years ago -- most of you know about it --
منذ ٦٥ مليون عاما – معظمكم يعلم عنه
we had an asteroid impact.
حدث إصطدام كويكبي
The Earth was struck by an asteroid,
تعرضت الأرض لكويكب
a huge amount of debris was jettisoned into the atmosphere.
تم قذف كميات الكبيرة من الحطام في الغلاف الجوي
Sunlight was cut off, and fungi inherited the Earth.
انقطعت أشعة الشمس، وورثت الفطريات الأرض
Those organisms that paired with fungi were rewarded,
تلك الكائنات التي قد اقترنت بالفطريات لاقت مكافأة
because fungi do not need light.
لأن الفطريات لا تحتاج إلى الضوء
More recently, at Einstein University,
و منذ فترة قريبة، في جامعة أينشتين
they just determined that fungi use radiation as a source of energy,
أكدوا أن الفطريات تستخدم الإشعاع كمورد للطاقة
much like plants use light.
كما تستخدم النباتات الضوء
So, the prospect of fungi existing on other planets elsewhere,
فاحتمالية وجود الفطريات على كواكب أخرى في أماكن أخرى
I think, is a forgone conclusion,
أعتقد أنه شيء مفروغ منه
at least in my own mind.
على الأقل في ذهني
The largest organism in the world is in Eastern Oregon.
أكبر كائن في العالم موجود في شرق أوريغون
I couldn't miss it. It was 2,200 acres in size:
لا يمكن أن أفوته. كان حجمه ٢٢٠٠ فدان
2,200 acres in size, 2,000 years old.
حجمه ٢٢٠٠ فدان وعمره ٢٠٠٠ عام
The largest organism on the planet is a mycelial mat, one cell wall thick.
أكبر كائن حي على وجه الأرض هو الميسيليال مات، سمكه خلية واحدة
How is it that this organism can be so large,
كيف يمكنا أن كائنا كبير بهذا الحجم
and yet be one cell wall thick,
و مع ذلك هو بسمك خلية واحدة
whereas we have five or six skin layers that protect us?
بينما نحن لدينا ٥ أو ٦ طبقات جلد لحمايتنا
The mycelium, in the right conditions, produces a mushroom --
الميسيليوم، تحت الظروف المناسبة، تنتج فطر
it bursts through with such ferocity that it can break asphalt.
تنشق بشدة كبيرة قد تحطم الاسفلت
We were involved with several experiments.
كنا مشاركين في عدة تجارب
I'm going to show you six, if I can,
سأعرض عليكم ستة ،إن استطعت
solutions for helping to save the world.
حلول لمحاولة إنقاذ العالم
Battelle Laboratories and I joined up in Bellingham, Washington.
أنا و مختبرات باتيل التقينا في بالينجهام ، واشنطن
There were four piles saturated with diesel and other petroleum waste:
كان هناك أربعة أكوام مشبعة بالبترول والديزل وغيرها من النفايات البترولية
one was a control pile; one pile was treated with enzymes;
واحدة كانت كومة تحكم، واحدة عولجت بالانزيمات
one pile was treated with bacteria;
واحدة عولجت بالبكتيريا
and our pile we inoculated with mushroom mycelium.
و كومتنا لقحناها بميسليوم الفطر
The mycelium absorbs the oil.
الميسيليوم تمتص الزيت
The mycelium is producing enzymes --
الميسيليوم تنتج إنزيمات
peroxidases -- that break carbon-hydrogen bonds.
البيروكسيديات -- التي تكسر الروابط الهيدروكربونية
These are the same bonds that hold hydrocarbons together.
هذه نفس الروابط التي تمسك الهيدروكربونات مع بعضها
So, the mycelium becomes saturated with the oil,
فتصبح الميسيليوم مشبعة بالزيت
and then, when we returned six weeks later,
ثم عندما عدنا بعد ستة أسابيع
all the tarps were removed,
جميع العوازل قد أزيلت
all the other piles were dead, dark and stinky.
جميع الأكوام الأخرى كانت ميتة، مظلمة ، ونتنة
We came back to our pile, it was covered
عدنا إلى كومتنا. كانت مغطاة
with hundreds of pounds of oyster mushrooms,
بمئات الأرطال من فطر المحارة -ـ
and the color changed to a light form.
و قد تحول اللون إلى درجة أفتح
The enzymes remanufactured the hydrocarbons
الإنزيمات أعادت إنتاج الهيدروكربونات
into carbohydrates -- fungal sugars.
إلى كربوهيدرات – سكريات فطرية
Some of these mushrooms are very happy mushrooms.
بعض هذه الفطريات سعيدة جدا
They're very large.
إنهم كبيرون جدا
They're showing how much nutrition that they could've obtained.
إنهم يظهرون كم من التغذية كان من الممكن أن يحصلوا عليه
But something else happened, which was an epiphany in my life.
و لكن شيئا قد حصل ، و هو ما كان بمثابة تجل في حياتي
They sporulated, the spores attract insects,
لقد أنتجوا أبواغا، و الأبواغ جذبت حشرات
the insects laid eggs, eggs became larvae.
الحشرات وضعت بيوضا. البيوض أصبحت يرقات
Birds then came, bringing in seeds,
ثم أتت الطيور، حاملة معها بذور
and our pile became an oasis of life.
و أصبحت كومتنا واحة للحباة
Whereas the other three piles were dead, dark and stinky,
بينما الأكوام الثلاثة الأخرى كانت مينة، مظلمة و ذات رائحة كريهة
and the PAH's -- the aromatic hydrocarbons --
والهيدرو كربونات الأروماتية متعددة الحلقات
went from 10,000 parts per million to less than 200 in eight weeks.
تحولت من ١٠٠٠٠ جزء بالمليون إلى أقل من ٢٠٠ في ٨ أسابيع
The last image we don't have.
ليست لدينا آخر صورة --
The entire pile was a green berm of life.
الكومة بأكملها كانت ساترا أخضر مليء بالحياة
These are gateway species,
وهذه الأنواع هي بمثابة بوابة
vanguard species that open the door for other biological communities.
طليعة الأنواع التي تفتح الباب لوحدات بيولوجية أخرى
So I invented burlap sacks, bunker spawn --
فقمت باختراع أكياس خيش -- مكان لحفظ البيض -ـ
and putting the mycelium -- using storm blown debris,
و لحفظ الميسيليوم -- باستخدام بقايا مبعثرة
you can take these burlap sacks and put them downstream
تستطيع أن تأخذ هذه الأكياس و تضعها عند مصب النهر
from a farm that's producing E. coli, or other wastes,
لمزرعة تنتج بكتيريا الإشريكية القولونية و نفايات أخرى
or a factory with chemical toxins,
أو مصنع مواد كيميائية سامة
and it leads to habitat restoration.
و تؤدي إلى إعادة الحياة للموطن الطبيعي
So, we set up a site in Mason County, Washington,
فأقمنا موقعا في مقاطعة ماسون، واشنطن
and we've seen a dramatic decrease in the amount of coliforms.
وشاهدنا انخفاضا كبيرا في كمية الكوليفورم
And I'll show you a graph here.
و سأريكم رسم بياني هنا
This is a logarithmic scale, 10 to the eighth power.
هذا مقياس لوغارثمي، ١٠ إلى القوة الثامنة
There's more than a 100 million colonies per gram,
هناك أكثر من ١٠٠ مليون مستعمرة في الغرام الواحد
and 10 to the third power is around 1,000.
و عشرة إلى القوة الثالثة تكون حوالي ١٠٠٠
In 48 hours to 72 hours, these three mushroom species
في غضون ٤٨ الى ٧٢ ساعة. أنواع الفطر الثلاثة هذه
reduced the amount of coliform bacteria 10,000 times.
اختزلت كمية بكتيريا الكلورفورم 10,000 مرة
Think of the implications.
فكر في التأثير
This is a space-conservative method that uses storm debris --
هذه وسيلة حفظ فراغ تستخدم حطام العاصفة -ـ
and we can guarantee that we will have storms every year.
و يمكننا ضمان حدوث عواصف كل عام
So, this one mushroom, in particular, has drawn our interest over time.
هذا الفطر، على وجه الخصوص، جذب انتباهنا على مر الوقت
This is my wife Dusty,
هذه زوجتي دستي
with a mushroom called Fomitopsis officinalis -- Agarikon.
مع فطر يسمى فومتسيس أوفيشينالس -- أغاركون
It's a mushroom exclusive to the old-growth forest
إنه فطر خاص بالغابة القديمة
that Dioscorides first described in 65 A.D.
الذي كان أول ما وصفه دياسقوريدوس في العام ٦٥
as a treatment against consumption.
كعلاج ضد الاستهلاك
This mushroom grows in Washington State, Oregon,
هذا الفطر ينمو في ولاية واشنطن، أوريغون
northern California, British Columbia, now thought to be extinct in Europe.
شمال كاليفورنيا، كولوبيا البريطانية، والآن من المعتقد انقراضه في أوروبا
May not seem that large --
قد لا يبدو كبيرا جدا
let's get closer.
لنقترب
This is extremely rare fungus.
هذا الفطر نادر للغاية
Our team -- and we have a team of experts that go out --
فريقنا – ولدينا فريق من المختصين الذين يخرجون للبحث
we went out 20 times in the old-growth forest last year.
ذهبنا إلى غابة النمو القديم ٢٠ مرة في العام الماضي
We found one sample to be able to get into culture.
وجدنا عينة واحدة قادرة على الاستنبات
Preserving the genome of these fungi in the old-growth forest
و تم الحفاظ على العوامل الوراثية لهذه الفطريات في الغابات القديمة
I think is absolutely critical for human health.
أعتقد أن ذلك في غاية الأهمية لصحة البشر
I've been involved with the U.S. Defense Department BioShield program.
لقد كنت مشاركا مع وزارة الدفاع الاميركية في البرنامج البيولوجي
We submitted over 300 samples of mushrooms that were boiled in hot water,
قمنا بتقديم أكثر من ٣٠٠ عينة من الفطر المغلية في الماء
and mycelium harvesting these extracellular metabolites.
و الميسليوم تحصد هذه الأيضات الخارج خلية
And a few years ago,
و منذ عدة أعوام
we received these results.
وصلتنا هذه النتائج
We have three different strains of Agarikon mushrooms
لدينا ثلاث سلالات مختلفة من فطر الأغاركون
that were highly active against poxviruses.
التي كانت نشطة للغاية ضد فيروسات الجدري
Dr. Earl Kern, who's a smallpox expert
الدكتور إيرل كيرن، الذي هو خبيرالجدري
of the U.S. Defense Department, states that any compounds
من وزارة الدفاع الأميركية ، تنص على أن أي مركبات
that have a selectivity index of two or more are active.
لديها مؤشرات انتقائية قيمتها ٢ أو أكثر تكون نشطة
10 or greater are considered to be very active.
١٠ أو أكثر تعتبر نشطة للغاية
Our mushroom strains were in the highly active range.
سلالاتنا الفطرية كانوا في المجموعة النشطة
There's a vetted press release that you can read --
هناك خبر صحفي يمكنك أن تقرأه
it's vetted by DOD --
تم فحصه من وزارة الدفاع
if you Google "Stamets" and "smallpox."
إذا قمت بالبحث عن Stamets" و "smallpox"
Or you can go to NPR.org and listen to a live interview.
أو يمكنكم الاستماع إلى المقابلة في بث حي على موقع NPR.org
So, encouraged by this, naturally we went to flu viruses.
متشجعون بهذا، اتجهنا إلى فيروسات الانفلونزا
And so, for the first time, I am showing this.
و لأول مرة أعرض هذه
We have three different strains of Agarikon mushrooms
لدينا ثلاثة سلالات مختلفة من فطر الأغاركون
highly active against flu viruses.
شديدة الفعالية ضد فيروس الانفلونزا
Here's the selectivity index numbers --
إليكم أرقام المؤشرات الانتقائية
against pox, you saw 10s and 20s -- now against flu viruses,
ضد الجدري، رأيتم العشرات و العشرينات -- الآن ضد فيروسات الانفلونزا
compared to the ribavirin controls,
مقارنة بمتحكمات الرايبافيرين
we have an extraordinarily high activity.
لدينا نشاط عالي بصورة ملحوظة
And we're using a natural extract
ونحن نستخدم خلاصة طبيعية
within the same dosage window as a pure pharmaceutical.
ضمن نفس الجرعة المعطاة كدواء نقي
We tried it against flu A viruses -- H1N1, H3N2 --
قمنا بتجربته ضد فيروس انفلونزا «أ» -- H1N1, H3N2
as well as flu B viruses.
بالإضافة إلى فيروس انفلونزا «ب»
So then we tried a blend,
ثم جربنا خليط
and in a blend combination we tried it against H5N1,
و في مزيج جربناه ضد H5N1
and we got greater than 1,000 selectivity index.
و حصلنا على مؤشر انتقائي أكبر من ١٠٠٠
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I then think that we can make the argument
أعتقد أن بإمكاننا بناء حجة
that we should save the old-growth forest
أن علينا إنقاذ الغابة القديمة
as a matter of national defense.
باعتبارها مسألة دفاع وطني
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I became interested in entomopathogenic fungi --
أصبحت مهتما بالفطريات المسببة للأمراض الحشرية
fungi that kill insects.
الفطريات التي تقتل الحشرات
Our house was being destroyed by carpenter ants.
منزلنا قد تم خرابه بسبب نمل الخشب
So, I went to the EPA homepage, and they were recommending studies
حتى أنني ذهبت إلى موقع وكالة حماية البيئة الالكتروني، وكانت هناك دراسات مقترحة
with metarhizium species of a group of fungi
بأنواع ميتارزيالية لمجموعة من الفطريات
that kill carpenter ants, as well as termites.
التي تقتل نمل الخشب، و كذلك النمل الأبيض
I did something that nobody else had done.
فعلت شيئا لم يفعله أحد
I actually chased the mycelium, when it stopped producing spores.
لقد قمت بملاحقة الميسيليوم عندما توفقت بإنتاج الأبواغ
These are spores -- this is in their spores.
هذه أبواغ -- هذه بداخل أبواغهم
I was able to morph the culture
تمكنت من تحوير الاستنبات
into a non-sporulating form.
إلى نوع غير منتج للأبواغ
And so the industry has spent over 100 million dollars
فأنفق مجال الصناعة ما يزيد عن المئة مليون دولار
specifically on bait stations to prevent termites from eating your house.
تحديدا على محطات الطعم لتوقيف النمل الأبيض من أكل منزلك
But the insects aren't stupid,
و لكن الحشرات ليست غبية
and they would avoid the spores when they came close,
وقد حاولوا تجنب الأبواغ عندما اقتربوا
and so I morphed the cultures into a non-sporulating form.
فحورت الاستنباتات إلى أشكال غير منتجة للأبواغ
And I got my daughter's Barbie doll dish,
و جئت بصحن دمية الباربي الخاص بابنتي
I put it right where a bunch of carpenter ants
ووضعتها حيث كانت مجموعة من نمل الخشب
were making debris fields, every day,
تشكل حقول غبار ،كل يوم
in my house, and the ants were attracted to the mycelium,
في منزلي، و انجذب النمل إلى الميسيليوم
because there's no spores.
لأنه لا توجد أبواغ
They gave it to the queen.
أعطوها للملكة
One week later, I had no sawdust piles whatsoever.
بعد آسبوع واحد، لم يكن عندي شيء من الغبار
And then -- a delicate dance between dinner and death --
ثم بعد انتظار
the mycelium is consumed by the ants,
الميسيليوم قد استلكها النمل
they become mummified, and, boing, a mushroom pops out of their head.
يتحنطون و يظهر الفطر من رؤوسهم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now after sporulation, the spores repel.
الآن بعد إنتاج الأبواغ، يتم التنافر
So, the house is no longer suitable for invasion.
فالبيت لم يعد مناسبا للغزو
So, you have a near-permanent solution for reinvasion of termites.
وبذلك يكون لديك حل شبه دائم ضد غزو النمل
And so my house came down, I received my first patent
و انهار منزلي، و تلقيت أول براءة اختراع
against carpenter ants, termites and fire ants.
ضد نمل الخشب، النمل الأبيض ، و نمل النار
Then we tried extracts, and lo and behold,
ثم جربنا الخلاصات، و لعجبي
we can steer insects to different directions.
يمكننا توجيه الحشرات في اتجاهات مختلفة
This has huge implications.
هذا له ضمنيات كثيرة
I then received my second patent -- and this is a big one.
ثم حصلت على براءة اختراعي الثانية -- و هذه كبيرة
It's been called an Alexander Graham Bell patent.
قد اسميت ببراءة اختراع الكسندر جراهام بيل -ـ
It covers over 200,000 species.
تشمل أكثر من ٢٠٠٠٠٠ فصيلة
This is the most disruptive technology --
هذه أكثر تكنولوجيا مدمرة
I've been told by executives of the pesticide industry --
لقد أبلغت من قبل المديرين التنفيذيين لصناعة المبيدات الحشرية
that they have ever witnessed.
التي شهدتها على الإطلاق
This could totally revamp the pesticide industries throughout the world.
هذا تماما قد يجدد مصانع المبيدات الحشرية في جميع أنحاء العالم
You could fly 100 Ph.D. students under the umbrella of this concept,
يمكنك إقناع ١٠٠ طالب دكتوراه بهذه الفكرة
because my supposition is that entomopathogenic fungi,
لأن فرضيتي بأن الفطريات المسببة للأمراض الحشرية،
prior to sporulation, attract the very insects
قبل إنتاج الأبواغ، تجذب العديد من الحشرات
that are otherwise repelled by those spores.
التي من ناحية أخرى تنفر من تلك الجراثيم.
And so I came up with a Life Box, because I needed a delivery system.
و لذلك قمت بابتداع "صندوق الحياة" لأنني كنت محتاجا إلى نظام نقل
The Life Box -- you're gonna be getting a DVD of the TED conference --
"صندوق الحياة" – ستستلم اسطوانة DVD لمؤتمر تيد
you add soil, you add water,
تضيف التربة، وتضيف الماء
you have mycorrhizal and endophytic fungi as well as spores,
عندك جذريات فطرية و فطريات اندوفية بالإضافة إلى الأبواغ
like of the Agarikon mushroom.
مثل تلك المشابهة لفطر الأغاركون
The seeds then are mothered by this mycelium.
ثم ترعى هذه الميسيليوم البذور
And then you put tree seeds in here,
ثم تضع بذور الأشجار هنا
and then you end up growing -- potentially --
ثم ينتهي بك الأمر إلى إنبات -- احتماليا -ـ
an old-growth forest from a cardboard box.
غابة قديمة من علبة كرتون
I want to reinvent the delivery system,
أريد إعادة ابتداع نظام النقل
and the use of cardboard around the world,
و استخدام الكرتون حول العالم
so they become ecological footprints.
حتى يصبحون بصمات ايكولوجية
If there's a YouTube-like site that you could put up,
إذا كان هناك موقع مثل YouTube يمكنك بدؤه
you could make it interactive, zip code specific --
يمكنك جعله تفاعليا، محدد بالرمز البريدي -ـ
where people could join together,
حيث يستطيع الجميع أن يجتمعوا
and through satellite imaging systems,
و من خلال أنظمة الأقمار الصناعية للتصوير
through Virtual Earth or Google Earth,
عن طريق Virtual Earth أو Google Earth
you could confirm carbon credits are being sequestered
يمكنك التأكد من أن أرصدة الكربون يتم عزلها
by the trees that are coming through Life Boxes.
من جانب الأشجار خلال صناديق الحياة
You could take a cardboard box delivering shoes,
يمكنك أن تأخذ علبة كرتون لنقل الأحذية
you could add water -- I developed this for the refugee community --
يمكنك إضافة الماء -- طورت هذا لمجتمع اللاجئين -ـ
corns, beans and squash and onions.
الذرة والفول ، والقرع ، والبصل
I took several containers -- my wife said, if I could do this, anybody could --
أخذت عدة حاويات -- زوجتي قالت أنه إذا كان بامكاني القيام بذلك، يمكن ذلك لأي أحد
and I ended up growing a seed garden.
وانتهى بي الأمر بزراعة حديقة بذور
Then you harvest the seeds --
ثم تحصد البذور
and thank you, Eric Rasmussen, for your help on this --
و شكرا لك يا إيريك راسموسين لمساعدتك في هذا الأمر
and then you're harvesting the seed garden.
ثم أنت تحصد حديقة البذور
Then you can harvest the kernels, and then you just need a few kernels.
ثم يمكنك جني البذور ، ثم ستحتاج إلى عدد قليل من البذور -ـ
I add mycelium to it, and then I inoculate the corncobs.
أضيف إليها الميسيلوم، ثم أقوم بتطعيم ذكر الذرة
Now, three corncobs, no other grain --
الآن، ثلاثة من الذرة، لا حبوب أخرى
lots of mushrooms begin to form.
فطر كثير يبدأ بالتشكل
Too many withdrawals from the carbon bank,
الكثير من الانسحابات من بنك الكربون
and so this population will be shut down.
و بالتالي فإن هذه الفئة السكانية ستغلق
But watch what happens here.
و لكن انظر ماذا يحصل هنا
The mushrooms then are harvested,
يتم جني الفطر بعد ذلك
but very importantly,
و لكن الأهم
the mycelium has converted the cellulose into fungal sugars.
أن الميسيلوم قد حولت السيليلوز إلى سكريات فطرية
And so I thought, how could we address the energy crisis in this country?
فتساءلت، كيف يمكن مواجهة كارثة الطاقة في هذا البلد؟
And we came up with Econol.
توصلنا إلى "الإيكانول"ـ
Generating ethanol from cellulose using mycelium as an intermediary --
إنتاج الإيثانول من السليلوز مستخدما الميسيليم كوسيط -ـ
and you gain all the benefits that I've described to you already.
و تحصل على جميع المزايا التي وصفتها لكم
But to go from cellulose to ethanol is ecologically unintelligent,
ولكن أن تحول من السليولوز إلى الايثانول ليست بفكرة
and I think that we need to be econologically intelligent
و أعتقد أن علينا أن نكون أذكياء من الناحية الايكولوجية
about the generation of fuels.
حول إنتاج الوقود
So, we build the carbon banks on the planet, renew the soils.
فنبني بنوك الكربون على كوكب الأرض ، نجدد الأتربة
These are a species that we need to join with.
هذه هي الأنواع التي يجب أن ننضم إليها
I think engaging mycelium can help save the world.
أعتقد أن استخدام الميسيليوم قد يساهم في إنقاذ العالم
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)